In the last video, we talked about what
a variable is and how it sets aside
memory on your computer and I used
different size boxes to demonstrate
that. So, in this video, we're going to
talk about the code that actually makes
that happen. So,
I'm going to click into my Visual Studio
Code and I'm going to talk about three
keywords. So there are three keywords
you can use when you want to set aside
memory on your computer to store
information. The first keyword and the
one that I use most often is the keyword
let. What the keyword let says is it
says set aside some memory. This memory
you can change what's inside of it but
just go ahead and set it aside. So I use
the keyword let and then I give the
variable a name. So using the keyword
let is like creating this box. This box
doesn't have a name. I said you probably
want to put something descriptive so
people know what's inside of it. So if I
was going to store a first name inside
this variable, then I'm going to use the
keyword let. That creates a box. And
then I am going to create the variable
first name.
That tells you what's inside the
variable. Some of you may have noticed
that I did something weird with the
casing on this variable. I used a
lowercase F and an uppercase N. There
are different variable naming
conventions and the naming convention
you use should be whichever one your
company uses. Whoever you're working
for, whatever they use, use that. If
there isn't a set standard, then be
consistent. So, I'm going to show you a
couple of different ways that you could
type this. So, the first is I could say
I'm going to make this a comment. So, as
a reminder, when you put in a comment,
it's two forward slashes or you can hit
command or control slash and that'll put
in the comments. So the first type, the
one that I used is called camelc case.
That's where you make the first letter
lowercase and then every start of a word
thereafter starts with an uppercase
character. So this is camelc case.
The next one we're going to talk about
is called snake case. This is often used
by people who develop in Python. Um but
it can be used with any language. And
that is you you type it all lowercase
and then you use an underscore and that
denotes the next word. So I could type
first underscore name and so this is
called snake case.
I could type um all uppercase for every
single word. So I could say first name
and we call this Pascal case.
Um, and there are others, but these are
probably the most common ones you're
going to see. Um, I like camel case, so
that's probably the one you'll see me
use throughout most of these videos. So,
I have now created I used the let
keyword that created a box. I'm now
putting a name on the box and I'm
putting a label across it that says
first name. That means that this
variable is going to store a first name.
Now, we could end it there. So, what
we've done is we've created a box and we
put a semicolon that says we are done
with this line. So, I've now created a
box and I've put a label on it called
first name.
I could now put something into that box.
One way you put something into the box
is you say first name equals and then
whatever you put on the other side of
the equals goes into that box. So, I
would say my first name is Toa and then
I'll put a semicolon and that ends that
line. So what I've done is I've created
the variable and then I've stored
something in it. We can actually do this
all on one line if we know what we want
to store in the box ahead of time. So we
can say let first name
equal to. So what that does is it says
create a box put a label on it called
first name. inside of that box store the
text toa.
The other type of variable, the other
way you can defer define a variable and
actually in this case what you're doing
is you're defining a constant is to use
the keyword const. So that's c o n s t
and then um we'll say const.
Trying to think of something that
doesn't change
const
happy. I am sometimes not happy. This
isn't a really good example, but we'll
create a constant and we'll store in it
um
the word true.
Oh, sorry. I've been coding in Python.
True is lowercase. Okay. What we've done
here is we've said create a box. That's
what the con does. It does the same
thing as let except it says create a box
and don't let anything change what's in
the box. So once I've put something in
the box, lock the box and don't let
anyone else get in there. So now for the
rest of our program, happy will always
be true. Later on, we can change what
the first name is, but we cannot change
what's inside of happy. So the happy
box, as because we've put it as a
constant, it does not change. So the two
keywords you'll most often use is let
and that's for when you want to create a
box that could have information that
changes and const is for when you want
to create a box where nothing changes.
This is helpful if you're like setting
up some settings for your app and you
want those settings to be the same every
single time your app runs. Then you'll
want to use const. Um, there is one
other way to create a variable and this
keyword works very similar to the
keyword let. You'll see it in people
who've been coding in JavaScript for a
long time because the let keyword didn't
used to exist. The let keyword is the
best way to create a variable, but um
you're going to work with other people's
code and so you're going to see other
ways to create variables. The last way
to create a variable is the keyword var.
There are some issues with the way this
creates a variable. So, I would avoid
using it if you can. Um,
but if you see someone else has it in
their code, um, just understand that it
creates a variable exactly the same way
let does. So, if I wanted to create a
last name, I'd say var last name equals
and then that's where I'd put my last
name. Um, and that wraps up our
discussion on how to create variables.
So in summary, let is for creating
variables that you want to change. Const
is for creating a constant that doesn't
ever change. And var is an old way of
creating variables that you might see
when you're working on your job. And
that wraps up this video. Thanks for
watching.